ANDREI CHOULGA

Email: nyc9293@gmail.com / LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/ac317 / cell: 646-714-2422 / US Citizen for DoD

EDUCATION:

NYU Grad M.S. in Cybersecurity / GPA 3.9/4 / Started QRCP Quantum Resistant Cryptocurrency Project **Brooklyn College:** B.S. in Computer Information Science (2006)

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:

Experienced professional with 20+ years of experience in Software Development with 8+ years of experience in the Cybersecurity field, is eager to contribute to company and team success. I bring research, test-driven development, detailed planning, documentation, and dedication to my team. I thrive in both team and individual settings, and welcome challenging projects that will take my skills to the next level.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Company: Ameritas (ameritas.com) New York, NY Position: Cybersecurity specialist - contract 10.2022-present

- Evaluated and improved security for all company services and infrastructure, worked with six different dev teams.
- Created Security Baseline Requirements based on NIST 800-53 controls, introduced threat modeling.
- Trained a security team to properly assess and triage new features for risk & work w. dev teams to remediate.
- Performed extensive **DAST** and **SAST** with API, Web and Apps, **OWASP** and **MITRE ATT&CK** based.
- Writing, scheduling, maintaining automated tests to check web, desktop and mobile apps (Android/iPhone) functionality in Dev, QA and Production environment.
- Performed vulnerability testing, risk analyses, security assessments on product lines for every release phase (BurpSuite, Mimikatz, Cobalt Strike, PowerSploit) Managed tests CrowdStrike and Rapid7 for clients.

Company: Cisco - Webex team (webex.com) Position: Cybersecurity specialist - contract

New York, NY 01.2022-08.2022

- Aligned security baseline to reflect NIST 800-53 by breaking it down into 15 security domains for CSDL Cisco Secure Development Lifecycle. Consulted Engineering teams to ensure secure development is implemented in all of our products, helped select the best solution & outcomes our security posture.
- Performed DAST (Invicti, Burp, ZAP) and SAST (Veracode). Ensuring compliance w. FedRAMP, SOC 2, FISMA.
- Managed and improved Vulnerability Management lifecycle (Helped migrate from Qualys to Tenable.io)
- Worked with developers on application security relevant to: **OWASP, SANS 25, Threat Modeling, API security,** Validating Encryption and Key Mgmt, Validating Identity and Access Mgmt, Validating Client security, Security hygiene - TPSD (Third-Party Software Digitization), Static/Dynamic analysis, X.509, OAuth.

Company: **NetworkShark** Position: Cybersecurity specialist - contract New York, NY

04.2014 - 12.2021

- Setting up DevSecOps CICD process automating it Qualis, Jenkins following NIST 800-53 controls baseline.
- Performed pen testing/DAST using Burp Suite, Acunetix, Kali Linux, Metasploit, Nessus; SAST (Checkmarx)
- Improved Docker+Kubernetes by setting up Terraform and HashiCorp Vault.
- via **Tenable.io** Interfaced with clients for whom vulnerability tests were done, explained what needed to be fixed.
- Automated vulnerability fix tickets into **Jira**, billing system and managed the vulnerability fixes.
- Managed public and hybrid cloud architectures in AWS, Azure (limited on Google Cloud)

Company: SAXO Bank - Software Engineer (2009-2014) / Company: FXCM - Software Engineer (2004-2009)

SKILLS/TOOLS:

Languages: C/C++, Java/J2EE, C#, Python, JavaScript (React.js/Node.JS/EmberJS/jQuery), Bash, PowerShell DB: SQL, MySQL, SQLite, PostgreSQL, KDB+.

Cloud: AWS - EC2, EKS, S3, IAM, RDS, KMS, CloudFormation, CloudWatch, CloudTrail.

DB: Oracle 8i-19c, MySQL, Cassandra, Redis, MongoDB **DB Tools**: IDERA, RazorSQL, Toad SQL.

Dynamic Application Security Testing (DAST): Acunetix, Kali Linux, Metasploit, Nessus, Wireshark.

Static Application Security Testing (SAST): Checkmarx, GitLab, Veracode, SourceGuard, Fortify SCA, AppScan Network Security / Monitoring: Splunk, Nagios, Argus, P0f. Proxy: Zed Attack Proxy (ZAP), Charles, Fiddler.

Web Vulnerability Scanning Tools: Burp Suite Pro, Paros Proxy, Nmap, Nessus Professional, Arachni.

SIEM platforms: Splunk, Datadog, QRadar (limited: AlienVault and LogRhythm).

Build Technologies & CD/CI: Jenkins, Teamcity, Apache Ant, Apache Maven, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform.

QA Tools: Selenium, Appium Stress test: LoadRunner, WebLOAD, Vegeta, locust.io

Other: SalesForce.com, Jira, Spring-Boot, Confluence, Git, Subversion SVN, Perforce, PKI.